Alexander Zapasnik

Software Engineer | Gdansk, Poland

+48 123 456 789 | mail@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/alexander-zapasnik/ | github.com/azapasnik

SUMMARY

I am an experienced software engineer with 11 years of industry experience specializing in backend web development and building scalable and reliable systems. I have experience leading teams, mentoring junior developers, and participating in hiring activities. Throughout my career, I have worked on projects in various domains, including geospatial analysis, e-commerce, and enterprise content management.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Jul 2018 – Present

Kontur, Inc

Kontur is a geospatial data and real-time risk management solutions provider for humanitarian, private, and governmental organizations.

- Architected and implemented 5 microservices utilizing 3 PostgreSQL DBs as a part of Kontur Platform
- Refactored several legacy services to a new tech stack, which helped to unify service configuration, deployment, and monitoring
- Conducted technical interviews for java backend position and helped to hire 6 backend engineers
- Worked with analysts and project managers on feature planning and estimations
- Conducted code review and mentoring

Skills: Java 8+, Spring Boot, JUnit, Gradle, PostgreSQL, PostGIS, Liquibase, MyBatis, Docker, Kubernetes, GIT, Gitlab CI, Github Actions

Software Engineer

*instinctools

Apr 2012 – Jul 2018

Grodno, Belarus

Software Engineer on E-Commerce team

Jul 2015 - Jul 2018

- Developed on-line shops on Hybris Platform for international retailer
- Implemented parts of custom platform for on-line shops. Migrated Hybris based shops to the new platform
- Mentored and trained a team of 5 junior software engineers
- Collaborated with project manager to establish sprint goals and plan to achieve them
- Worked in Agile environment utilizing Planning Poker and Kanban board

Skills: Java 8, Spring Boot, JSP, JUnit, SAP Hybris 5.5, Maven, Apache Solr, GIT

Software Engineer on Enterprise Content Management team

Apr 2012 - Jul 2015

- Developed document automation for Incoming, Outcoming, Organizational and Finance documents
- Implemented analytical reports

Skills: Java 7, JSP, EMC Documentum, Oracle DB, Tomcat, SVN

Software Engineer

Oct 2009 – Apr 2010

 $Crossmart\ RB\ LLC$

 $Grodno,\ Belarus$

• Developed warehouse inventory management application

Skills: Borland Delphi, MySQL

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Information Technology Software

Sep 2009 - Jan 2014

Yanka Kupala State University of Grodno

Grodno, Belarus

LANGUAGES

English: C1 Polish: B1 Russian: Native